[
    {
    "question": "Information technology (IT) is the use of computers to __________ data and information.",
    "option1": "store",
    "option2": "retrieve",
    "option3": "store or retrieve",
    "option4": "None of the above",
    "answer": "store or retrieve",
    "explanation":" Information technology (IT) is the use of computers to store or retrieve data[1] and information. IT is typically used within the context of business operations as opposed to personal or entertainment technologies",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Easy"
},
{
    "question": "IT is considered to be a subset of?",
    "option1": "IST",
    "option2": "ICT",
    "option3": "IDT",
    "option4": "IOT",
    "answer": "ICT",
    "explanation":" IT is considered to be a subset of information and communications technology (ICT).",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Easy"
},
{
    "question": "The term information technology in its modern sense first appeared in a ________.",
    "option1": "1930",
    "option2": "1937",
    "option3": "1948",
    "option4": "1958",
    "answer": "1958",
    "explanation":"The term information technology in its modern sense first appeared in a 1958 article published in the Harvard Business Review",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Easy"
},
{
    "question": "Data transmission has _________ aspects.",
    "option1": "1",
    "option2": "2",
    "option3": "3",
    "option4": "4",
    "answer": "3",
    "explanation":" Data transmission has three aspects: transmission, propagation, and reception.",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Easy"
},
{
    "question": "The relational database model introduced a programming-language independent Structured Query Language (SQL).",
    "option1": "TRUE",
    "option2": "FALSE",
    "option3": "Can be true or false ",
    "option4": " Can not say",
    "answer": "TRUE",
    "explanation":"True, The relational database model introduced a programming-language independent Structured Query Language (SQL), based on relational algebra.",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Easy"
},
{
    "question": "Which one is the first search engine in internet?",
    "option1": "Google",
    "option2": "Archie",
    "option3": "Altavista",
    "option4": "WAIS",
    "answer": "Archie",
    "explanation":"Archie one is the first search engine in internet.",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Medium"
},
{
    "question": "Number of bit used by the IPv6 address?",
    "option1": "32 bit",
    "option2": "64 bit",
    "option3": "128 bit",
    "option4": "256 bit",
    "answer": "128 bit",
    "explanation":"Number of bit used by the IPv6 address 128 bit",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Medium"
},

{
    "question": "The planning information requirements of executives can be categorized into three broad categories?",
    "option1": "Environmental info",
    "option2": "Internal and competitive info",
    "option3": "Both A and B",
    "option4": "None of the above",
    "answer": "Both A and B",
    "explanation":"The planning information requirements of executives can be categorized into three broad categories Environmental info, Internal and competitive info.",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Medium"
},

{
    "question": "Accuracy, purpose, relevance, validity and timeliness are the features of? ",
    "option1": "Data",
    "option2": "Information",
    "option3": "Knowledge",
    "option4": " All of the above",
    "answer": "Information",
    "explanation":"Accuracy, purpose, relevance, validity and timeliness are the features of Information",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Medium"
},

{
    "question": "Database Management Systems (DMS) emerged in the 1960s to address the problem of storing and retrieving large amounts of data accurately and quickly.",
    "option1": "Yes",
    "option2": "No",
    "option3": "Can be yes or no",
    "option4": "Can not say",
    "answer": "Yes",
    "explanation":"Yes, Database Management Systems (DMS) emerged in the 1960s to address the problem of storing and retrieving large amounts of data accurately and quickly.        ",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Medium"
},
{
    "question": "Which was the first purely object oriented programming language developed?",
    "option1": "Kotlin",
    "option2": "SmallTalk",
    "option3": "Java",
    "option4": "C++",
    "answer": "SmallTalk",
    "explanation":"SmallTalk was the first programming language developed which was purely object oriented. It was developed by Alan Kay. OOP concept came into the picture in 1970â€™s.",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Hard"
},
{
    "question": "Which header file is required in C++ to use OOP?",
    "option1": "OOP can be used without using any header file",
    "option2": "stdlib.h",
    "option3": "iostream.h",
    "option4": " stdio.h",
    "answer": "OOP can be used without using any header file",
    "explanation":" We need not include any specific header file to use OOP concept in C++, only specific functions used in code need their respective header files to be included or classes should be defined if needed.",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Hard"
},
{
    "question": "The feature by which one object can interact with another object is _____________",
    "option1": "Message reading",
    "option2": "Message Passing",
    "option3": "Data transfer",
    "option4": "Data Binding",
    "answer": "Message Passing",
    "explanation":"The interaction between two object is called the message passing feature. Data transfer is not a feature of OOP. Also, message reading is not a feature of OOP.",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Hard"
},
{
    "question": " Which of the following is not true about polymorphism?",
    "option1": "Helps in redefining the same functionality",
    "option2": "Helps in redefining the same functionality",
    "option3": "It is feature of OOP",
    "option4": "Ease in readability of program",
    "answer": "Increases overhead of function definition always",
    "explanation":"It never increases function definition overhead, one way or another if you don't use polymorphism, you will use the definition in some other way, so it actually helps to write efficient codes.",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Hard"
},
{
    "question": "What is an abstraction in object-oriented programming?",
    "option1": "Hiding the implementation and showing only the features",
    "option2": " Hiding the important data",
    "option3": "Hiding the implementation",
    "option4": "Showing the important data",
    "answer": "Hiding the implementation and showing only the features",
    "explanation":"It includes hiding the implementation part and showing only the required data and features to the user. It is done to hide the implementation complexity and details from the user. And to provide a good interface in programming.",
    "category":"it",
    "complexity":"Hard"
}


    
]